DELUSION
Where's Yod now?
I'm supposed to go home now.
And he told me I could go home now.
You can go home soon.
I need your help here, Uncle.
Hmph.
You worked at headquarters, yeah?
Mmm.
Commendations in a senior position, too.
Yeah.
Uh…
Now, Uncle,
what can you tell me about this ghost?
What happened?
Hey,
who got taken this time, huh?
A boy named Mued. Grandson of Paew.
Grandson of Paew?
Hey, Paew doesn't have a grandson.
Her son isn't even married.
Ah, that's okay, Uncle.
It doesn't matter.
In any case,
would you be able to help me?
Who is Phii Pong?
Look,
people believe that the spirit
only possesses adults.
The truth is, it's in children.
Kids?
Yeah.
You mean your grandson?
Grandson?
Who's that?
Oh. The son of your daughter
who came into the forest.
Is Aim Phii Pong, Uncle?
I don't know that.
All I know is he's a kid,
but I don't know whose child he is.
So, we're done here, right?
I'm going home now.
Not yet, Uncle. I've just got
a few more questions for you.
Let me out of here!
What am I locked up for, anyway?
I'm a civil servant, dammit!
- Calm down.
- Let me go!
- Come on!
Uncle, calm down. I'm just trying to talk.
I don't give a damn who you think you are!
I'm not afraid of you
because I didn't do any of it! Let me go!
Sergeant, can we get a DNA sample?
Nee!
Come and talk to these people for me.
Nee! Come here!
CHIANG KHAN HOSPITAL
How could you let that happen
to our child?
The police told me everything.
You're lucky I'm not pressing charges.
Charges for what?
For playing with his own grandson?
I'm taking him home right now.
And you'll dump him at your mom's
while you go somewhere else.
Why shouldn't he stay with me?
Hasn't he told you?
He doesn't want to go to Grandma's.
Better than a house
with a crazy bastard walking around.
Even if you leave,
he'll stay with me, anyway.
Your family is so poor.
How could you give him a good life?
You can't even keep him fucking safe.
Poor, sure.
But I didn't leave him
to go out and fuck around.
I'm only seeing one person.
And I'm happy.
So stop talking nonsense.
People will get the wrong idea
and think she's my mistress.
Just agree to the divorce.
Everyone…
can tell we don't love each other.
Pa!
- Aim. Oh!
- I'm okay. See?
Oh, my son!
You all right, little boy? Oh.
Listen, you're staying
at my house tonight. Okay?
Oh! You know, you had me worried sick.
Let me look at you. Oh.
Oh, okay. Okay, you're okay. You're okay.
2014 MURDER CASES
CASES 1-10
Uh, Inspector?
"Phii Pong Murders."
Are these all the files from the time?
Yes, Inspector. This is all we have.
We don't get many big cases around here.
MURDER CASE FILE
Ah, that one. That's the Phii Pong case
from more than ten years ago.
THONGDEE SUMPLOY - COMPLAINANT
POL. LT. SOMSAK PATHAM - RECORDING OFFICER
Be careful not to scratch it too much,
or it'll scar.
But it itches, Mom.
Does it hurt?
Um, only a little.
You know when soccer running hurt my chin?
That was worse.
Hmm. Let's see.
Oh.
- The doctor did a good job.
- Ooh.
- Aim.
- Hmm?
Sorry.
What are you sorry for?
You don't have to be sorry.
Aim, why did you follow Grandpa
into the woods?
Hmm?
I wanted to know if Phii Pong was Grandpa.
Grandpa is just unwell.
You and I know that.
Um, I wanted to get some proof.
Because everyone was saying things,
and I wanted to know the truth.
Hmm.
But did Grandpa scare you?
How did you end up in the water?
You can go back with Dad.
I have to stay and look after Grandpa,
but I'll be back soon, okay?
- Mmm-hmm.
- Come on.
Hold on a second, Wat.
- Aim?
- Mmm?
Did you forget something?
Pew.
- Bye-bye.
- See you soon.
I'll call you, okay?
Come on.
All these murder cases,
you're the only one still around?
Yep.
Because then, there were only a few of us.
Now they're all either dead or retired.
So what do you think, Sergeant?
Think?
Is it a ghost or a person?
I may be small-town,
but I'm not an idiot, Inspector.
But back then, we couldn't talk to anyone.
It did cross my mind
it could be a ghost.
City guy like you probably hears that
and thinks we're ridiculous, right?
Sis, they're keeping Dad in custody.
What the… What?
Can they do that?
Well, I think it might be better
if Dad stays here for a while.
Because if something happens
while he is here,
maybe they will stop saying
he is possessed.
What about Ma?
She's here with me.
I'm about to take her home.
See you at the house.
So, he moved here, yeah?
That's right, Inspector.
Hey there.
Sir, a few questions.
Can I help?
This is our new inspector.
Hello, sir.
I'm here to ask about your son.
I didn't think much of it.
Around here, it's normal for kids
to be playing out in the fields.
If I'd known there was an evil ghost,
I never would have let him go.
Thinking carefully,
did anyone from outside the village
move in at that time?
That I remember, no, Officer.
Aside from Phii Pong,
is there anyone else you suspected?
There was no ghost.
Do ghosts hunt and kill kids?
The cops were just lazy.
They repeat what others say
so they don't have to do their jobs.
Hey, Bua.
Your son wasn't killed by a ghost.
No? Well, who do you think did it then?
I don't know. That your job, isn't it?
And who brought up Phii Pong
for the first time?
If it wasn't the cops,
it was the shaman around here.
Just repeating the same thing for years
while nobody bothered to look
for the person who killed my son.
I'm sorry, officers.
Just heat up the leftovers and eat that.
The day is wasted.
There's no time for anything now.
Okay, I will. Do you take
your medicine before you eat?
Are you doing anything later this evening?
Take me up, up to the police station.
Your father's on his own.
He's not in his right mind.
We can't leave him there.
I'll go on my own.
Now just look at the mess we're in.
It would have been all right,
but you had to go and call the police.
And now they've locked him up.
The whole town is gossiping.
Here, put this in the fridge for me.
Wan.
Can you please lend me some cash?
I don't have any.
You don't have any? What do you mean?
Your husband is rich.
His family is rich as hell.
And what about you?
Don't you have any savings of your own?
My savings? I send you money all the time,
don't you remember?
Are you getting dementia as well?
Take your medicine.
Here, sis, let me help.
Come on. Let me help.
Is this enough? If not,
I can make an omelette.
Plenty, sis. It's great.
Hardly, when her son is eating, too.
Hey, do we have any chilly?
Add lots of chilly, okay?
Make it really spicy.
The way we used to eat it
when we were kids, remember?
Oh, and, um, Dad's hospital bills,
I can sort it out.
And about Mom wanting to borrow money,
I'll give it to you.
You transfer it to her.
Why don't you just give her the money,
and leave me out of it?
If you're lending her money,
don't start with it all.
Hold some back.
Just in case we have to put Dad
into permanent care.
Mm.
Poor Aim falling in the water.
Did he end up saying who did it?
Um, it wasn't Dad, was it?
Aim really loves his grandpa.
He just slipped.
Dad tried to help him, but he couldn't.
Oh.
Hmm.
Regarding the cause of death,
it was a severe blunt force trauma
to the head.
We found absolutely no defensive wounds.
So it's very probable
that one blow caused death.
Or at the very least,
immediate loss of consciousness.
Sergeant, you can step out if you need to.
Yeah, I'll be outside.
What about the wound on his abdomen?
Well, this injury is postmortem.
So it happened just after
the victim has been killed.
Is it possible to determine
what weapon was used?
It's hard to say, Inspector.
All we know is that
it was a sharp, hard object.
If you find any potential weapons,
uh, around the crime scene,
we can compare them.
Okay.
Oh, yes, and he tested positive
for amphetamines.
WOUND ASSESSMENT FORM
ANUPONG NALAH
Do you think it's possible
the perpetrator is the same
for these cases?
This is another case
from more than ten years ago.
The victim's teeth were also taken out.
Both cases show
very similar patterns of death,
especially with the missing teeth.
I'd be surprised if there's not
more evidence at the crime scene.
I'm sure you'll find some answers there.
Sergeant.
- Hmm.
- We need to follow up on the evidence.
Um, I'm gonna get going, sir.
There you go.
People are scared.
He's in custody for now.
He's not a suspect, I'm assuming.
You know,
the closest person to the scene
was your dad.
And we found a grey hair on the body,
so he's a person of interest.
We've sent it for DNA testing.
If it doesn't match, there's no issue.
You can't be saying
someone in my dad's condition
is capable of this.
I mean, it's hilarious
that people still believe
in this Phii Pong craziness.
Back then, how do you remember it?
I don't.
Someone died near your home.
Weren't you a little scared?
No way.
Not about it being a ghost.
And so were there any rumors or gossip
about the identity of Phii Pong?
No, there wasn't.
I remember people started hanging
those scarecrows.
You've got a younger brother, right?
Did he hang one?
No, he didn't.
Ma put one up.
Although my dad didn't really believe
in it. He just let her hang it.
But not long after,
he sent my brother to study in Bangkok.
MURDER CASE FILE
You're from the city,
but you believe in ghosts?
You seem so fascinated by it.
I think you're starting to believe
that my dad's a ghost.
If not, that's good.
Justice will prevail, and I know
my dad will be treated properly.
Open up!
- Ugh, what is it now, old man?
- Open the door! Open it!
Open it!
Dad!
Dad, wait a second. I'll ask the officer.
Tell me why I'm locked up in here.
But you're not.
You're helping them investigate.
But it is a secret,
so the door has to be locked.
What do you need, Dad?
I need the bathroom.
Open up.
It's okay.
Dad, just go with the officer, okay?
I'll be here, all right?
Yeah.
If you can keep your dad
from going anywhere,
then maybe we can release him.
So you can rest up.
Won't it hurt him, tying him up like this?
Well, just how it has to be for now.
But I'll find something that works better
at the psych ward.
Also, I've adjusted his medication.
If he stops having these mood swings,
we won't have to tie him down.
I can watch over him.
Sis, get some sleep.
- I put in my share.
- 100 baht each. I've given.
- Who said that?
- I remember now.
That's what happened.
You went to the cremation, right?
- You went, didn't you?
- I did.
- Did you go?
It was very sad.
I'm sorry for your loss.
BORN 9 SEPTEMBER 2011
DIED 31 OCTOBER 2026
What are you making?
Fish congee.
Here, let me help you.
Ey, Nee.
Where's your husband?
At home.
- Wat is helping to look after him.
- Huh?
The police let him out already?
Mmm.
And what if he runs off again, Nee?
Why didn't you leave him
with the police for a while?
Stupid to let him out.
What if the Phii Pong possesses him again?
Hello, Shaman Sak.
Hello.
My condolences.
Human teeth are really tiny.
Hard to find.
Hmm. How many are missing again?
Mmm, how many?
Five.
Two incisors, one canine,
and two molars.
Ready?
The drone is ready, Inspector.
The boy went in pretty deep.
Hold up.
What's that?
- Sergeant.
- Yes, sir?
Back then, who knew
this house was here?
In the old days, you couldn't
get this deep in the forest, sir.
So nobody knew that it was here,
or who built it?
And today we're going to prove it,
the story of Phii Pong here in Nasao.
- What's the truth behind it…
- Nee!
Nee, are you home?
Nee!
Nee, are you there?
Who is it?
How should I know?
What are you doing here?
Let Sak do a ritual.
It's no big deal. You're better off safe.
Come on now, we're all family.
This isn't so hard.
Now I'll just go in and speak
to Narong for a while.
Please come back. He's asleep now.
Are you two alone in there?
How about Wat?
Wat's at work.
Come on, go.
You're going to wake Narong up.
Who is it?
Let me go!
- Sadhu, sadhu, sadhu.
- Stupid snake oil idiot.
Truly, the Blessed One is worthy.
Homage to the body of Buddha.
Bind it. Bind it.
I said, let me go!
Uh, Inspector, we found some more teeth.
The spot we found Mued,
and the place
where the mechanic's kid was found
are both near the hut.
Guts.
Teeth.
Blunt force to the head.
Phii Pong.
Sergeant, maybe we pay
that shaman a visit.
Wanna skip taekwondo today,
and eat shabu?
Can we do it later, Mom?
I've got my red belt exam. I wanna pass.
Are you sure you're ready for it?
It's in the bag.
Wanna come see Grandma and Grandpa?
How about that?
I have to work tomorrow,
so we can come back together.
Okay.
Will Dad mind?
Never mind. Go with Dad.
If you came with me, we'd have
to wake up early, anyway.
I'll see you tomorrow though.
Hello, Grandma.
Oh, I see your car.
I'm coming out now.
Here. Dad's old phone is mine now.
Chew that properly, dear, or you'll choke.
You're eating like that before class?
Won't you feel sick?
Mmm-mmm.
Mom, see you soon.
Mmm-hmm. Ooh.
Pssh.
Hello.
Is Yote with you?
Yote's a busy man.
What's he up to?
He told me he'd pick up Aim.
If he's too busy to come for his son,
he should have let me know.
I'm here now.
Yote had something come up suddenly.
Oh, but you don't need to worry.
Because I will keep
my grandson safe from harm.
Bye-bye now.
Don't want Aim to be late.
What the hell?
- Yote?
- Don't come out. There's glass here.
YOTE
Wan, I never thought
you could sink this low.
Now let me tell you something
Doesn't matter what you say,
doesn't matter what you do,
because you could hold a gun to my head,
and you'll get nothing from me!
Between you and me,
there is nothing left.
I never considered playing dirty.
But if that's way
you want to play it, game on.
And you know,
forget about your son.
You'll never see him again, or my money.
- He's here.
- Mm.
- Hello, Uncle.
- Hello. What brings you here?
Have you been drinking?
I only just arrived here,
so I had my colleague
bring me to see you.
What name should I use, Sarge?
Master or Shaman?
Oh, we just usually call him--
Just call me "Uncle."
Uh…
And what's your name, son?
I'm Pete.
How long have you been doing this, Uncle?
Quite a while. More than ten years.
Ever since Phii Pong
killed the mechanic's boy, am I right?
Well, I don't recall.
You knew the kid named Mued.
I'm working on that case.
And everyone keeps saying,
"It's just like back then,
the case of the mechanic's boy."
I bet you got some stories.
I don't really know anything, you see.
These stories that the old folks
passed down,
that's about it.
It was already happening
before that kid died?
Beware the angry spirit.
Everyone around here knows about it.
Is that right?
Yeah.
Mm.
But you left out some details.
You said Phii Pong only eats human organs.
But the bodies we found
were missing other things.
Hmm?
A spirit will eat anything
that's on the table.
It only needs to be careful
not to let anyone who has seen it
tell the world who it really is,
or else the soul it possesses will die.
So Phii Pong is like a thief, then?
Okay, that'll do.
Let's go, Sergeant.
I'll be counting on you, Uncle.
Hmm.
Oh, wait.
Here. Here.
Mm.
Take this.
Keeps ghosts away. Keeps evil out.
Thank you.
SRI CHIANG KHAN STREET, SOI 19
Three bags for 100 baht. They're suede.
Two porridge and steamed rice. One bowl.
Sure thing.
You two should have a beer.
I can drive you.
Un, well…
Are you sure
that's a good idea, Inspector?
Ask me again and I'll say "No."
- Oh, hey, two beers, please.
- Coming.
Here.
That's all there is. That's all I've got.
Is that all?
Hello?
Yes, I am.
Inspector, the DNA results just came in,
and the DNA does not match Mr. Narong's.
I've sent you some information
by email.
Please take a look at it, Inspector.
Cases like this have happened
in other provinces.
And in every case,
teeth were missing from the bodies.
That plot of land,
it's a waste for it to sit empty.
Sign it over.
You've taken enough. No way.
That's all!
Back then, how do you remember it?
I remember people started hanging
those scarecrows.
MUED
It wasn't the cops.
It was the shaman around here
just repeating the same thing for years.
How long have you been doing this, Uncle?
Quite a while. More than ten years.
Ever since Phii Pong
killed the mechanic's boy, am I right?
Subtitle translation by: Parida Kim